Jacques Diambra-Odi

2496 Piering Dr. Stonecrest, Ga 30038

E-mail: jodiambra@gmail.com

Cell: (678) 409-0623

https://www.linkedin.com/in/jodiambra/

Portfolio: jodiambra.github.io/

Data Scientist

SUMMARY:

Self-motivated, curious, diligent, and goal-oriented Data Scientist eager to apply my Python skills to solve critical business problems. With a background in science, I bring over 8 years of analytical thinking, data analysis, and problem solving to the table. I am currently a Quality Control Chemist at a global chemical manufacturing company, with work experience in chemistry, biology, genetics, and public health.

Skills

Programming: Python, Scikit-Learn, Pandas, SQL, EDA, Statistics, Git, Web scrapping

Data Visualizations: Plotly, Matplotlib, Tableau, MS Excel

Machine Learning: Regression, Classification, Clustering, Gradient Boosting, Time Series, BERT, Keras,

Deep Learning, NLP, Computer Vision

Technical Experience

Code Pudding, 12/2022

- Collaborated with software engineers to build a website for our project
- Led a team of 4 to conduct exploratory data analysis and statistical analysis on Spotify playlists
- Discovered popularity trends was correlated with music events and pop culture: music awards, fashion shows, movies, super bowl, festivals

Ice Retail, 11/2022

- EDA on video game retail store sales
- Created interactive visualizations, identified patterns that lead to successful sales
- Formulated plan for advertising campaign to maximize profit in regional markets

Sure Tomorrow Insurance, 12/2022

- Applied machine learning to identify similar customers
- Predicted whether a customer was likely to receive an insurance benefit
- Predicted the number of insurance benefits a customer was likely to receive
- Protected clients' personal data with obfuscation, without affecting model performance

Sweet Lift Taxi, 01/2023

- Used ML on time series data to predict the number of orders during peak hours
- Tested different regression models, tuned hyperparameters, and chose the best model for the task

Professional Experience

QC Analyst (2019 - present)

Arxada

- Analyzed chemical, raw materials, in-process materials, or release test samples in support of compliance with company standards
- Interpreted and evaluated the analyses in terms of accuracy and precision compared against established specifications; recommended, and implemented corrective action where necessary
- Successfully took on the challenge of analyzing a 120% increase in lab samples
- Reduced the analysis time for HPLC azole method by 130%
- Team lead of 3 chemists

Research Associate I (2016 - 2019)

Research Corporation University of Guam

- Teamed with 2 researchers in successfully identifying pro-inflammatory molecules involved in Areca nut carcinogenesis, using HPLC fractions (doi: 10.1038/s41598-017-18996-2)
- Contributed to leading-edge Areca nut carcinogenicity data; compiled, analyzed, and interpreted results leading to 1
 publication, and Areca nut intervention studies with Guam Cancer Research Center
- Presented data to community at conferences and developed further studies and experimental designs to address similar research concerns

Research Lab Assistant (2011-2013)

PITT Dept. of Biological Sciences

- Enhanced quantitative and qualitative analyses, such as sampling, testing, and measuring using specialized equipment, shaving 10% off analysis times
- Conducted DNA miniprep (purification) experiments with drosophila DNA with minimal supervision, followed experimental protocols

Education

- o **Data Science,** Practicum Bootcamp (2022-2023)
- Master of Science in Biology, NIH/U54 Scholar, University of Guam (2016-2019)
- o **B.S. Biology,** University of Pittsburgh (2010-2016)

Other

- o Judo tournament champion, Jiu-Jitsu tournament 3rd Place (2015)
- o Former D1 Soccer walk-on (PITT 2013)
- o University of Guam Men's Soccer Team Player/Coach, Women's Championship Team Coach (2016-2019)
- o Guam National Soccer Team (2003-2010)
- o Assistant Soccer Coach, University of Guam Summer Camp (2017-2018)
- Cryptocurrency enthusiast